Saiteja Boppana

Web Developer

- O Hyderabad, INDIA
- **\(+91 8919068182**
- boppanasaiteja1995@gmail.com

Skills

Web Technologies

HTML 5, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, Node JS

Web Frameworks / Libraries

React JS, Redux, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Angular, Jest, React Testing Library(RTL)

Tools

Git, Jira, Webpack, Vite

Languages

English

Telugu

Hindi

Profiles

in Saiteja Boppana LinkedIn

Summary

Web developer with 6 years of experience in building large scale and accessible web applications in diverse domains using top JS frameworks. Specializes in **front-end technologies** and passionate about modern web standards and evolving development trends. Looking forward to full stack opportunities that helps me to further scale up my abilities.

Work Experience

EPAM Systems

Nov 2021 - Present

Software Engineer

Hyderabad

- https://www.epam.com/
- Made significant Contributions in the development of web applications in multiple domains of banking and agritech etc.
- Addressed application performance issues and was responsible for optimizing app performance by 20%.
- Responsible for fixing production level incidents within stipulated timelines.
- Mentored a team of three junior dev's in one of my projects, which led to their increased technical abilities and productivity levels.

Mindtree Ltd

Feb 2018 - Nov 2021

Software Engineer

Bangalore

- https://www.ltimindtree.com/
- Involved in the development of web application suite for a major real estate firm based out of US markets.
- Owned responsibility for integration of third-party apps/services such as Google Tag Manager (GTM) analytics library and feature flags service LaunchDarkly into our web application.
- Involved in the design and implementation of POC's related to new application services within internal company platforms.

Education

Gudlavalleru Engineering College

June 2013 - April 2017

Gudlavalleru, AP

Bachelors in Computer Science

Narayana Junior College

June 2011 - March 2013

Vijayawada, AP

Higher Secondary Education

Digital Storefront

A digital trade platform offering various agri based **July 2023 - Present** services.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- This project adopts agile software development methodology, and my role is an individual contributor as web dev.
- Writing well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices.
- Worked on Next JS (App Router) and gained good exposure with learning caching and rendering strategies.
- Worked on API integrations, configuring and setting up Jest framework with RTL in our application.

Digital Banking Platform

An all in one digital platform which offers various Dec 2021 - May 2023 banking services to its diverse customers.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Made Contributions as an individual dev and in addition, mentored two junior dev's in the project.
- Worked extensively with third party libraries like Formik for maintaining forms, Yup for field validations and middlewares like Redux Sagas.
- Actively collaborated with product owner and BA on requirement fine tuning, inform about risks involved and work out on feasible options.
- Engaged in the development of various digital banking features for one of the reputed banking clients based out of SG.
- Responsible for development and maintenance of micro frontend applications (MFA's).

Realogy APM

A Real estate firm offering digital services to its agents **June 2020 - Nov 2021** and clients.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Involved in the development, publishing and maintenance of reusable
 UI components within our custom npm packages.
- Worked with Reactive forms(Angular) and also integrating third party libraries like Okta for authentication and Launch darkly feature flag services.
- Involved in bug fixing, triage and writing unit tests.
- Developed profile manager application for real estate agents and worked on embedding it in other client applications.